<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AkiDAY</title>
    <link>https://astronomen.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AkiDAY</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astronomen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phonon Coherence and Polaritons of Excitons</title>
      <link>https://astronomen.github.io/post/phonon_coherence_exciton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://astronomen.github.io/post/phonon_coherence_exciton/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Phonon coherences reveal the polaronic character of excitons in two-dimensional lead halide perovskites&amp;rsquo;
Introduction Hybrid organic-inorganic metal halide perovskites have become an interesting area in materials science owing to their unique optical and electronic characteristics, and have been widely used in the preparation of optoelectronic devices such as solar cells[1]. The distinct lattice structures of these quantum well-like derivatives result in unique behaviour. To elucidate the peculiar nature of these materials, Félix Thouin and his colleagues delve into the interaction between excitons and phonons in 2D lead halide perovskites, providing significant insights into their polaronic nature and the resultant impact on their optoelectronic properties in the paper I reviewed, which confer both structural flexibility and remarkable electronic characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Trends in Astrocomb</title>
      <link>https://astronomen.github.io/post/astrocomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://astronomen.github.io/post/astrocomb/</guid>
      <description>Abstract—The motion of star systems will cause a Doppler shift on the spectrum, providing valuable insights into the dynamics and characteristics of celestial objects. Astronomical deep space exploration necessitates the use of high-precision astronomical spectrographs to analyze the subtle variations in Doppler shift observed in stellar absorption lines. Astrocombs serve as essential tools for the precision calibration of astronomical spectrographs, playing a crucial role in advancing the fields of cosmology and exoplanet research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultra Violet C Irradiation Grating Coupler Design</title>
      <link>https://astronomen.github.io/post/uvcgrating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://astronomen.github.io/post/uvcgrating/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ultraviolet (UV) irradiation is defined as a type of electromagnetic radiation, with a wavelength (100–400nm) shorter than that of visible light (400–700nm), but longer than x-rays (&amp;lt;100 nm)[1]. Ultra Violet C irradiation (UVC) ranges from 100 to 280nm in wavelength. UV irradiation is divided into four distinct spectral areas including vacuum UV (100–200 nm), UVC (200–280 nm), UVB (280–315 nm) and UVA (315–400 nm)[2].
Due to its power to damage the genetic material (DNA and RNA) of microorganisms, which can prevent them from producing, UVC irradiation is widely used in disinfection and sterilization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquid Crystal Actuator and Ink-jet Print</title>
      <link>https://astronomen.github.io/post/lc-actuator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://astronomen.github.io/post/lc-actuator/</guid>
      <description>This paper is collaborated between me and my colleague Songyu Yao. This is our literature review of Printed artificial cilia from liquid-crystal network actuators modularly driven by light, which is written by Casper L. van Oosten, Cees W. M. Bastiaansen and Dirk J. Broer on Nature Materials.
Introduction of Basic Concepts Liquid Crystals Liquid crystals (LC) are materials with anisotropy, the position of molecules can be randomly arranged, which means it can flow like a liquid, but the molecules are fixed oriented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://astronomen.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://astronomen.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Here is Zhifan (Charles) Dai. For convenience, you can just call me Zhifan, or call my English name Charles directly. And now I am a master student of photonics engineering at University Ghent.
Welcome to my personal blog website in English, where I archive my personal resarch collections and works.
This static site is generated by Hugo and is deployed on Github Pages. This blog is using Clean White as the theme, thanks to zhaohuabing for such great works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://astronomen.github.io/categories/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://astronomen.github.io/categories/review/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Review&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://astronomen.github.io/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://astronomen.github.io/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts Archive</title>
      <link>https://astronomen.github.io/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://astronomen.github.io/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
